okay we'll start again uh we left with
three
questions uh Buddha said you can take
all these beings to Nirvana but when
they get there nobody gets
there and
uh then uh Master kamila started to look
at the person in three different
versions the first is the one that goes
to Nirvana so first they're in sansara
like they're yelling back at their
husband and and then it happens again
right so they they are and then we teach
them that what the husband does is
coming from how they treated the kids
last week and then they break out of
that cycle
so I don't know in March there was a
woman who was yelling back at her
husband and in August she's free of that
but what connects them the woman in
March to the woman in August you know
what is the thing which connects those
two people because
otherwise the lady could yell at her
husband in uh in March and then in April
uh some other ladies husband will yell
back at her as a result you see what I
mean there' be no connection between
them because Buddha said there's no
person there's no Michael so if there's
no Michael then what connects the person
who's having trouble with the person who
gets out of trouble what connects them
okay then the second question
was what was the picture on the second
one the PO the postman right who brings
you back your the letters that you wrote
to
yourself okay and then people always
shoot
the M messenger they yell at the postman
which is your
husband uh
so what connects the person what what
words did kamila use the eater and the
doer yeah what connects the eater and
the doer what connects the person who
who makes the karma to the person who
eats the karma or experiences the karma
what if there's no
Michael Buddha said there's no Michael
or nobody reached nirvana then who
connect what connects those two uh why
can't uh you know why can I do something
on Wednesday and Nick experiences it on
Friday what what makes
me and the third question was it was the
prison my mom's face my mom's face right
like how can I there were two questions
how can I recognize and how can I
remember you know the person who was
taken care of by their mom and then the
person who 20 years later can pick her
out of a crown and said that's my mom
okay so who connects the
two the next photo is a
butterfly butterfly and uh
caterpillar okay so butterfly and a
caterpillar so this is Master K's
answer and I think it's the coolest
thing in the whole week I think it's the
most interesting thing and it was hard
to translate
uh he used a word called gak G so g
means India K KCK means um gak cake
means a special bug in India uh called a
a lack insect or lack caterpillar
La uh and
lack like nowadays when they make a
something out of wood you will paint it
and the paint is made with chemicals
right uh but 100 years ago they didn't
have those chemicals and they used to
use natural substances one of the most
one of the ones most in use in the whole
world was called Lac and it came to be
called lacer or
shalak you know I mean and there's an
insect called Lac lack buug and he lives
in India and uh he's like a
caterpillar and he makes a little house
for himself out of I don't know
something and it looks like a little
tube okay and then he crawls inside and
then he lives there and if you smash
that tube and you make powder out of it
then you can use it to paint things uh
it's a very it's a natural varnish and
it used to be one of the main products
from
India uh so in tibetan the word is
kak so Master kamla Sheila says
somebody's making a
cocoon somebody's making a tube okay
somebody's making a cocoon the the the
lady who was responding to her husband's
criticism by saying no you're stupid
crawled into the cocoon in
April then she got educated but in
Buddhism and then in in August out came
a lady who's no longer in this little
sansara she understands that her husband
is yelling at her because she yelled at
her kids last week and because she wants
to shut her husband up
she she she stops yelling at the
kids and that's so cool you don't have
to negotiate with your husband you don't
have to say anything to your husband you
can change him without telling him which
is always better to do things without
telling your husband
so you can uh you know you stop you
figured out that the reason he calls you
stupid every night is because you call
your kids stupid
then you just to to take care of that
you stop yelling at your kids and then
when the seeds are all used up he stops
yelling so that woman is enlightened
she's reached marital Nirvana she uh
doesn't have this little cycle anymore
sansara that's a real sansara forget
these big Grand Saras you
know big Grand Saras are made of little
ones so
she she fixed the problem she can't and
what connects the woman who used to yell
at her husband in the jail with the
woman who got out of the jail is a
cocoon there's a cocoon
okay then the obvious question is who
made the
Cocoon okay
who who connects the the her in August
to the her in April who who made the
connection she did she did okay she did
the seeds in her mind are making the
Cocoon the seeds in her mind are making
the connection between the woman who was
in jail and the woman who got out of
husband jail okay that cocoon that tube
was created by her
seeds so what are the seeds
to what are the seeds to have a coherent
self what what are the seeds to feel
like oh I I'm doing much better now in
August my husband's he shut up when I
come home he gives me a hug that I
deserve and I don't have these problems
anymore you know
who who created the coherent self that
that says I used to in in April I was
yelling in August I'm free who who
creates this sense of unity or coherence
or a coherent self over time who created
that I did what's the karma to create
that helping others I he doesn't get
into it but you can you can guess I
think it's it's honoring
others people you know like as a p
person you know like giving them
self-esteem helping others to have
self-esteem you know a healthy sense of
self okay a healthy sense of self who
that's the karma that creates a healthy
sense of myself a healthy
cocoon a healthy cocoon over time which
is Michael Then I then I feel good about
myself and I I feel connected with
myself what happens if you lose that you
get like a autistic person or you get
like a person with
Alzheimer's and you cannot you know you
see your own daughter in the nursing
home and she came yesterday and she
asked you you know did you like the
movie on Monday and you're
like you lose your sense of connected to
your past self even yesterday or or last
week you can't
remember who you were and you start to
lose your sense of self okay so that's
an
indication that the sense of self over
time the Cocoon is created by yourself
and you can lose it you can lose
it uh low self-esteem is a
example extreme Alzheimer's is a is an
extreme example you can't remember your
own daughter or your own son and you
can't remember what happened last week
and it's easy to talk to those people
because they just ask you the same
questions every day
yeah so gu I was thinking about it
yesterday and I came to this point with
the like autism or someone Alzheimer's
my question to myself then was that does
that person with autism or Alzheimer's
how can they plant a seed for them to
then you know like for their future life
or whatever cuz there's still some
coherency right their mind just fall off
the yeah I think there's I I was
thinking a lot about it cuz uh he
doesn't go into it so deeply what the
cause is he doesn't go into the karmic
causes but I was thinking uh once you
start recognizing other people you know
even with
meanness you know then uh you create a
Karma to be to have a sense of self and
I I I have a theory that you can never
lose it completely I agree I don't think
you can lose it completely I think you
when did you first have a sense of self
is there's no beginning every living
being of the six kinds that exists in
the
universe insects have some sense of self
people with extreme a autism or
Alzheimer's they still have some sense
of
Stu so I think you can't lose it you
cannot become non
sensient I don't think so there's
something about being a thinking being
that perpetuates being a thinking being
I I think so when did they start who
made them in Buddhism it's an illegal
question okay you know scientists feel
they have to say there was a first day
of the world but Buddhist say there was
no first day cuz there had to be a day
before to cause
it uh so we think it's illogical to say
there should have been a big bang or
something cuz nothing could have caused
it uh so we don't think it's logical we
think it's it's only logical to say that
every living being thinking being what
was the third one individual being who
exists right now has always existed okay
yes
please uh I'm sorry if you already
talked about very Misty um but why did
they say three kinds of beings um like
he says conscious beings living beings
and person individual yeah is it
connected to the the three meditation
that you gave us in a way that the first
one is um talks about the other people
the first one talks about being in jail
and getting out of
jail yeah uh thinking being
and then the living being Liv is one who
did karma and got it back and then uh
individual being is one who had an
experience and remembered it later so I
think there is a connection and I think
he's older than kamalashila I think he's
repeating an older tradition that that
maybe went back to the Buddha I think so
I think so so basically it's the same
this just to emphasize he does it three
times to emphasiz he he he doesn't
clearly draw a connection between those
three and the three in the Sutra but I
think you can and I think it was an
older tradition I think maybe Buddha you
know why Buddha has to say three people
you know uh I think it's because he
wants us to think about SAR and Nirvana
karmic cause karmic result and
experience and memory of that experience
I think he wants us to be aware of three
kinds of cocoons three kinds of cocoons
and they cover most of the cocoons there
are I
think the only other detailed commentary
is chony Lama and he's not that clear on
it I think there's a I think there's a
older correlation between those three
and the three in the
Sutra and for Kamil it was just natural
it was still alive in his time the
tradition okay
so you make your own cocoons and and
you're the one who gives you a sense of
self or over time a sense of
continuity and I think the karmic cause
is is honoring other
people as as a person you see what I
mean like there's a some people like
they just treat other people like
they're just machines
or you know like you see the guy in the
grocer store who's working in the
grocery store and he's making all this
stuff for you and you're like yeah okay
you don't like say thanks or how are you
or good morning but the minute you say
good morning to someone I think you're
planting the seeds for a
cocoon you're recognizing their
individuality and you're recognizing
them as a
person and and that then what's
interesting if that cocoon is coming up
from
seeds you C in in Tantra you can rewrite
the
stories okay in Tantra you can write a
different version of your life so I had
a
relationship the the guy got
abusive uh he ran around with other
ladies and then finally I got rid of
him and then I found the Dharma and a
new
partner then
maybe he was a Buddha you know maybe he
was pushing me to get so Mis able that I
would seek spiritual guidance you know
what I mean like it gets very suspicious
you know like if you don't study Tantra
then he's just a bad
guy but the more you study Tantra then
the Cocoon
changes you rewrite the Cocoon it's very
interesting that's what Tantra is all
about and it's not that you're
pretending he was an angel logically you
decide he must have been you know it's
so cool where I got to because of him
that he must have been somebody special
you know I hate him more than anybody
but he was
special you know he did something great
for me you know he got me to where I am
now you know he got me into the Dharma
he got me to a better relationship more
experienced relationship and
then you know then you the point is
if the Cocoon is coming from your karmic
seeds you can adjust the Cocoon you can
rewrite the Cocoon you see what I mean
so your
history over time you could start
to what's it call it
revisionism you know maybe your whole
life has been
magical maybe every boyfriend whoever
split up with you was pushing you to
diamond mountain or something you know
you don't know in in Tantra you you you
explore
that and you have to have morality as a
basis of Tantra because that creates
enough good seeds to want to rewrite
your history or to think the history
might have been different the reason
Tantus start to believe their
ex-boyfriend might have been a Buddha is
that they've been following their
morality very strictly and that's the
basic tantric vows the five Bud
vows the the the shared it's called the
shared vows of the five
Buddhas what's the unique vow of the
five
Buddhas check your behavior six times a
day keep a book okay that's the five
Buddha fam's unique vow the shared vows
are the 10 Good Deeds because if you
keep doing the 10 Good Deeds you have
enough good Karma to start thinking your
ex-boyfriend might have been a
Buddha okay and then you slide into
Tantra people always ask me can I have
an initiation there's two ways to get
into tant one is an initiation you
know and one is you just slide in there
naturally cuz you're following your
you're you're keeping your book you're
following your vth keeping your
Bou and then you then you can have the
idea that maybe my boyfriend was a
Buddha the the guy who who hurt me maybe
he was a Buddha he got me some place
okay so you change your G kick you
change your cocoon your lack insect
cocoon okay
question yeah
okay okay I don't understand the three
ones uh if I continue questions the
third one or all three cocoon yeah third
cocoon is uh I hurt my knee when I was a
kid my mom came and you know cleaned the
cut and she put a banding on the cut and
that was a younger version of my mom
then I went to college I moved to
America and I met my mom after 20 years
and she said here's the address I'm
staying with my friends then you go to
that address you open the door there's
three women there and
like Mom you recognize your mom so there
must be some connection between the
person who was the kid who cut their
knee and the mom who's in the house with
the other three moms because you can re
remember her you can recognize her okay
that's
all
first second Karma and yeah doer and
eater is doer and eater the one who
makes the karma and the one who gets it
back you can call boomerang thrower and
Boomerang
Smasher we're like all day long we're
like you
know and then third one is uh original
experience and
rememberer or there's two parts or
recognizer who recognizes their mother
or who remembers their
what happened what their mom did my
question that because
everyone why when the one BEC a Buddha
he becomes
every I didn't catch the last part why a
Buddha becomes everyone yeah they don't
every Buddha is individual so when you
reach
buddhahood you you don't melt into the
other buddh they're all individual okay
they reached the same state of mind they
can all see the future the past and the
present but they don't become one person
that's not true they they are individual
Buddhist say that for
example Bud uh has the essence of all
the Buddhist like same state of mind but
not that he's not the one who was mandri
during Gama's time
yeah he's he's not he doesn't exist as M
there's different different mindstream
and you stay separate this the you your
mind
is how do you talk to somebody who knows
everything what my my llama said one day
he was teaching in New York he said what
do Buddhist do after they get
enlightened you know am I going to tell
you the
news you
know and he said oh they just did enjoy
they just hang
out yeah okay yeah but separate
mindstream
question
basically the question is about now you
think that we can transform our past you
can rewrite your past and then uh now
so can we go back to our past and change
the past so that our future which is
related to the Past can also be
transformed yeah you
for basically G what what you are
teaching us is to do something right now
at present to to change whether our past
or future so if that's the case can we
go back to our past because I think past
present and future are all they they all
exist at the same time so can we go back
to the past and do something there and
change our present now and the future
yeah in in in the sense that not by
wanting not by
willpower but by changing your seats
okay it's like the pen is coming from me
but I cannot change it into a Diamond by
wanting right but if I change my seeds
then that pen becomes a a tool for
changing the world I see the pen
differently so if I change my seeds then
the way I see my ex-boyfriend changes he
become an angel who's trying to help me
that changes
me that different vision of my boyfriend
changes me the Buddha thought I was
important enough to come and break up
with
me I'm special okay like that okay all
right so when you change your when your
seeds change your past of course it
changes who you are now and and who
you're going to be in the future
okay all right question I want to ask a
question about children you know that uh
the personality and behavior of children
are always similar to their parents and
so how to explain of the relationship
between the children and the parents
yeah
good
the it's interesting okay uh in the mind
only school there's a very important
idea which is when you meet
somebody like you meet somebody on a
train they sit down next to you on a
train and you start to talk to them okay
then
in the mind only School you and that
person have come out of one seed one
seed open and split into two branches of
a tree but they both came from here's
the trunk tree trunk here's the two
branches of the tree and there's a kic
seed here so this seed is
planted uh by being nice to your
friends then one year later you're on a
train it grows girl it girls it girls
you're on a train and you sit down and a
cute boy sits down next to
you okay and actually you created him
and you created you to be in the same
place at the same time okay
so the reason that so many children are
like their parents or or why I don't
know if the parents an alcoholic often
times the child is an
alcoholic the child created the
parent you created the parents that you
were born born to okay that you you
created the reason you are similar to
your parents is that you created them
okay you came you both came from the
same
seed okay very interesting so it's
difficult to break out of that cycle If
the parents are
abusive uh often times the the child
becomes abusive also because actually
they created an abusive
parent they were abusive two lifetimes
ago or something and they and that's why
they were born in an abusive family okay
it's very then you get into the blind
Turtle it's so hard to break that cycle
you know to get out of a cycle of abuse
because it came from you okay one more
question then we got to go back to
Cil thank you cuz I got pancakes waiting
for me I
know thank you for teaching us so in a
so unique way in unique place yes which
bring us unique
experience you should write our
advertising question is from that lady
so it's about meditation number n and 10
n iing everybody okay so in China we
have a strong idea in Buddhism that we
should practice to
be uh treating people without
discrimination in the sense of
equinity um
so if like if we encounter some
dangerous situation should we be like a
Buddha like feeding our meat with the to
the tig to the tiger or should we
protect ourself first how should we
balance because our life is so uh uh
rare so uh so this question is about
equality yeah okay China is a big
concept okay we're going to talk about
it today it's it's on the subject it's
on the list
today but in
general
in the practice of
giving you should never make a gift
which is so large that you will regret
it later because the regretting is a
very bad karma so so I I was with my
Lama one day he was a refugee he came to
America with a a cardboard suitcase with
like two two sets of robes in it he
didn't have any money nothing completely
broke he didn't see a dentist for 50
years that was an experience and then uh
I was with him we went down to
Washington
DC and this lady he gave a great
teaching and the lady took us in the
kitchen afterwards and she said this
house is yours here's the title here's
the Deeds I sign it over to you you take
it he said no you keep it I'm like
freaking out you know you know we're
totally broke we're totally broke the
Volkswagen with 200,000 miles on it just
blew up on the highway Blew Up in Flames
you know I'm like just take part house
you
know you know and he's like no I don't
want it and I later I was like I said
why did you do that and he said she will
change her mind later she will regret it
later then that's a very bad karma that
becomes a much it's much worse Karma
than than the Good Karma of giving the
house cuz she will say oh maybe I
shouldn't have given it to him
I was you know I was a what do you call
a moment
of yeah happiness about the teaching and
then I I'm sorry I gave him a house okay
so uh in
Buddhism when you're deciding whether to
give your flesh to a a hungry dog or
something you have if you have
that if you're at that level you can do
it that's okay to do but if you if
you're not at that level it's a very
wrong thing to do you shouldn't go over
your capacity cuz later you'll regret it
and then then it's a very bad karma okay
so just give what you can give
comfortably and happily and think about
it carefully to give money is a
difficult thing to give away money is a
difficult thing it takes a lot of
maturity it takes a lot of common sense
it takes a lot of practice giving away
stuff is not easy okay okay let's go
back to the text uh he says next
next up he wants to talk
about this whole subject is who goes to
Nirvana why why doesn't anybody to go to
Nirvana he's discussing reason he did
the person first the reason he said
nobody reaches Nirvana is that that's
the first one you always see directly
Joe's the first emptiness that Joe sees
directly will be the emptiness of Joe
it's always that I'm not who I thought I
was okay
so he starts with the person he has one
more thing to say about the emptiness of
people then he's going to go to The
Emptiness of other stuff okay so here's
the the picture here is the happy lady
okay what number I don't know 1 17 17
yeah it's this happy lady okay happy
lady she's the person you took to
Nirvana she's like thank you so much I'm
so happy okay I'm so happy okay then the
question comes did you make her
happy
yes you see did you make her happy you
taught her you know probably you taught
her you took her up in a
dome and you taught her shamata and then
you T her Viana and then she got to
Nirvana and she's so happy then the
question comes did you make her happy
happy
it's you taught her and then she
became
happy okay you taught
her and then she
became happy I usually do this with a
microphone at DCI talk I bang on the
microphone you T I did the first time I
did it was in Russia that wasn't the
best place to do it the first
time I'm like
you taught her and and then she became
happy right you made her happy my
husband makes me miserable you know
okay then finally this russan guy got
put
your why are you doing this why are you
banging on the microphone while you're
giving the talk just stop it I said I'm
sorry I have to bang on the microphone
he said what put you move why why are
you doing that I said I do this every
day he says well I don't care why are
you doing it today I said every time I
do this the next morning the sun comes
up think what's going to happen if the
sun doesn't come up no crops nobody goes
to work you know I got it I got to do
this every day why every time I do it
the sun comes up the next day he says
but but it's not connected I said what
do you mean he says that's not why the
Sun comes up it's just a coincidence you
do that and the sun comes up but it's
not
connected did you make her happy by
teaching her V and Sham you see what I
mean did you make her happy now cause
and effect right I give a class you
reach nirvana I give a class you reach
nirvana I see a person who's kind of
happy and then I see a person who's
totally happy okay there's a person I
don't know kunga okay her name is means
happy but that's
different so she's like kind of normal
person sometimes happy sometimes sad
then I teach her all this stuff then the
next time I see
her she's got Nirvana she's kunga with
Nirvana kunga K
Nirvana and the the day before she was
just kunga okay so question is did I
make her
happy
yeah did I make her happy then we have
to say no okay but what happened what
happened between today and yesterday get
Now
understand yesterday I had bad seeds in
my mind yesterday I had lower seeds in
my mind and they made a normal kunga
those seeds made a normal kunga just the
normal sometimes happy sometimes s kunga
okay then suddenly who seeds improve
your my seeds my seeds suddenly got
better next day they're making a kunga
who's who who has happiness but did I
did teaching her make her happy no no my
seeds made a normal kunga then the next
moment the next day with an
unreasonable transition period boom
she's got
Nirvana she's totally happy okay it's
unreasonable she doesn't go slow B you
can't even point to the place and that's
a sign that it's not coming from her
side I cannot point to a moment when she
flipped
over there's no such moment was it 1205
1206 1205 and 1 second or was it 1205 in
1 second and a half when did she Boop
when did she flip over there's there's
no gradual becoming Buddha there's one
picture from my mind and then there's
another picture from my mind it's just
two pictures from my mind
okay in 165th of a
second okay my mind is making 65
pictures a second then at 64 she she's
still kind of unhappy then at 65 she's
totally happy but I didn't make her
happy okay no one can make you
happy okay he makes me so unhappy you
make yourself
unhappy okay you can't make somebody
happy
then then hang on then kamila puts it
threeways okay he says if you think
about
it human language is
broken human language is broken how do
we talk about happiness number one I am
happy come on you are
happy yeah my name's
happy you know in English we say I am
happy but what's that mean you know you
just suddenly change into happy you know
I
am happy and but then or so in that case
you are 100% happy I
am happy this part happy this part's
happy every part's happy I am Michael
happy equal you see what I mean I am
happy then the other choice is I feel
happy here's happy here's me I feel
happy okay got it in that it doesn't
make sense then Happy's out there I'm
over here I I make contact with happy I
oh look feels
good okay no it doesn't make sense the
language is broken I am
happy I feel
happy I got
happy I didn't have happy then I got
happy you see what I mean or I became
happy you know I was no happy then I
became happy every part become happy the
all the words are
broken you can't be happy you can't feel
happy and you can't become
happy okay it's just a new picture
coming where from where out of your mind
you can't make anybody anything didn't
you notice that yet
K I'll make you waffles it'll make you
happy I'm like okay let's do it then
they make a lot I have waffles I eat
them then I'm like oh
man you know the intention was to make
Gea happy but you
can't you can't it depends on his seeds
you if he has good waffle seeds he'll
stop after the he'll stop after the one
and a half and he'll say I feel happy
you know but you cannot make him Happ me
because it doesn't work every person you
tried to make happy three things
happened they got happy nothing happened
and they got angry there's only but you
can't control it it it depends on their
SC you see you cannot make person happy
you cannot make them you cannot make
them be happy you cannot make them feel
happy you cannot make them become happy
you don't have the power because they're
not coming from you sorry they are
coming from
you okay what they feel is coming from
their
seats that's why you shouldn't get
discouraged when you try to help people
and they get mad at you you take your
daughter to a l room
Retreat and you say isn't that wonderful
and she says Mom this is all weird you
know then uh you can't guess what
they're gon to do you can't guess you
try to try to make another person happy
is a good
karma but but you can't whether you
succeed or not it's not up to you it's
up to them do they have seas to be happy
you see all you can do is make the
waffle then whether or not they're happy
after the waffle it's not your problem
okay and you shouldn't stop making
waffles if somebody gets angry after
this third waffle you know what I mean
you shouldn't say okay I give up helping
people I tried to help five people they
all turned on me they all got nasty they
all wrote things about me on the
internet I'm going to give up helping
people you know you know that that's a
non- Buddhist thinking okay they have
their own seeds you do your best to help
them maybe they get happy maybe they
don't that's that's up to their seeds oh
so should I give up trying to make
people happy no because it makes you
happy and then it and then it helps
other people because they see that
you're happy and they okay so you got
the the purpose of that next meditation
which is more
difficult is can you be
happy can you feel happy and can you
become happy okay and you have Kam
Sheila he gets this is where it gets
really nasty the commentary gets really
hard I put a question on it Mark on
every line that's hard and around here
all of them have
question okay last one for
today now Buddha if you check your
diamond cutter okay later something
radical happens uh he
says by the
way oh by the way if you thought you
were going to take on to Nirvana you're
no bodh sappa I won't call you a bodh
sappa then he gets more radical he says
when Buddhist offers help people they
don't stay in
anything and he gives five examples they
don't stay in what they see they don't
stay in what they hear six examples they
don't stay in what they smell they don't
stay in what they taste they don't stay
in what they touch and they don't stay
in what they think the six
senses okay they don't stay there so
what's that mean okay when they do their
giving they don't stay in anything okay
when they bodh safas practice which
Perfection the first one they don't stay
in the things they see in the things
they hear or even in the things they
think and he's only giving the first six
of the datus there's 18 total we'll talk
about it okay he already talked about
the emptiness
of people he's going on to the emptiness
of things okay he's moving on to the
emptiness of things and he says when I
give something to kunga like a I'm not
going to give you my
handkerchief
yeah that's good when I give her a okay
when if I'm a bodh SAA and I want to
help her you know I want to become a
Buddha I have to practice the six
Perfections he only mentions giving
because he didn't want the suture to go
on too long it it means all six
Perfections but we're just using giving
as an example so when I give to
her something as a bodh SATA I'm not
staying in the gift and I'm not staying
in her and I'm not staying in me and
what does that mean and then Kam Shila
goes
off he goes whoa he goes you know he
says first of all there's three kinds of
giving we have four
in five Buddha families they're supposed
to
do three times a day and three times at
night I think
okay
okay that's the
verse sing means
stuff candy
bars okay laptops uh money that's called
the first kind of ging is called s sing
okay s sing the second one do you
remember anybody from the tant class at
Dime
Mountain I looked it
up huh H that's the last one yeah
protection who said yeah mik mik
literally means freedom from
Fear give people Freedom From Fear
okay but there's a special
interpretation in the Buddha five Buddha
familyes teaching do anybody
remember it means what Stanley was just
talking about okay that's why I said it
was coming it means to to do equal to
everybody equal towards everybody a
tiger is hungry feed them your your
child is hungry feed them equally with
equal concern okay so when you say to
give Freedom From Fear in the teaching
of the five Buddha families what you
mean is to treat everyone equally it's a
special thing because that's kind of
protection or Freedom From Fear okay
Ming then CH means DH giving the Dharma
give the teachings teach the dharm these
are these are the three that Master
kamla Sheila mentions he doesn't mention
the last one which is love okay these
are the
four kinds of giving that you're
supposed to practice three times a day
and three times in the evening in the
dark and three times in the light which
is a tantric B of which
Buddha good I looked it up rakar
Southern Buddha yellow Buddha okay this
has The Vow
of the yellow Buddha which probably is
why the mental Affliction that's related
to him is and stinginess stinginess yeah
so okay you give it up okay so so at at
this place Master kashila says three
kinds of giving he says Buddha talking
about three kinds of giving the love is
assumed we're talking bodh saas we're
talking people trying to save the world
the Love Is we don't have to mention it
okay then he says you can split the six
Perfections up between the three types
of giving and that's why Buddha doesn't
have to mention the other five
Perfections in the diamond C
Sutra okay so giving stuff is
giving treating people equally is a kind
of morality and a kind of
patience okay treating people equally is
a kind of morality morality should be
equal treat everybody the same don't
hurt anybody and it's a kind of patience
I don't care how anger you get I'm going
to treat you nice okay okay so that the
second one the gift
of freedom freedom from fear or the gift
of equanimity is the is the second and
third the second and third uh
Perfections
okay the giving the Dharma is the last
three
Perfections okay which
is
effort
meditation wisdom and wisdom then he
gives a definition of effort which I was
struggling with okay the fourth
Perfection and I finally it hit me in
the head if Kamala Shilo spoke English
and if you asked him what's the fourth
Perfection he would say have
fun have fun okay and it applies to all
the other Perfections you know when
you're giving somebody a candy
bar you know like have fun don't be
like okay okay like have
fun so in Buddhism if you're religious
you're having more fun and you're
supposed to be having more fun and it's
everything is supposed to be more fun
okay okay it's really fun you can call
joyful effort but it's too
long
fun okay uh just have fun doing it then
he says you can't teach the Dharma
unless you think it's fun because it's
going to take a lot of effort okay it's
going to take a long time to learn it I
want all of you to teach Kamala Sheila
okay we could have a on you know we
could have Kam Sheila Retreats here
every three months or something you know
every four months we could have
a one of you or three of you could teach
kamila part
one here in this room with a new batch
of people and we could keep that going
forever you know it it's the pictures
it's the photographs you know it's you
just tie the meaning to the photograph
so you look at the photograph and you
talk and and and we could keep having it
could be a big deal at Diamond Mountain
is unique Kam Sheila Retreats you know
that and and you have to teach them
okay and that would be
fun what was the intention with which
Lord buddas went into meditation at the
beginning of the
sutraa this lineage should not breaken
yeah that's that's why he talked you
know kamila says the reason Sab stood
up why didn't the Buddha just teach the
SRA himself why did sa have to stand
up because the next Link in the lineage
is starting now that's why sa Buddhist
stands up okay it's cool you know Lord
Buddha starting the lineage now right
now and you guys should pass it on in
China or wherever you are teach
comination teach this teach this two
three day thing you can make it a
weekend thing and you can use the
photographs and teach it just teach it
okay you can be
saaby there's a later theory that sabui
was
mjusi in
Disguise and he wanted to bring up the
questions okay uh there's a later
tradition that he was a Buddha a Buddha
was talking to a Buddha you want to
pretend to be a student this is all
going on in their mind you hey Nick you
pretend to be a student oh come on I was
a student last
time okay just let me come on you know
Veronica's hair I want to look like the
teacher you know okay
G okay so uh anyway so he mentions three
kinds of giving
right and then he says when when Buist
do that kind of giving they don't stay
in it okay they don't stay in it it
means is that the lunch
bill okay three spars we had it in jeta
three spars
okay Su
Roa who made the smell The Taste the
this the yellow color the blue color uh
who made the touch of it you know my
seeds the reason I have something to
give to kunga is is I gave something
before and that's why I have something
to give to kunga okay so a bodh sappa
doesn't just throw in a candy bar he's
like
oh yeah I made each of those qualities I
made how it feels I made how it smells I
made how it tastes I made how it looks
okay I made everything
okay and because of that knowledge they
want to give it cuz they want
more okay so and then oh I made coua the
one that I'm giving it to you know I
made this nice smiling face and and a
beautiful nun and I I made her so while
I'm giving it I can say nice job Gish
Michael you know you made a nice nun you
know no this is how buddy St for things
and then who put us here
together okay it's just two branches of
the same tree you know I created her I
created me to give her the the thing I
came here from a seed that I planted she
came here from a seed that I planted and
I planted this to here have it and
then no and that's the Perfection of
giving that's the Perfection of giving
what's the results from that kind of
giving he's going to talk about later
okay we'll get to
that tomorrow or Sunday we we are going
to finish the whole thing which I
couldn't do in Taiwan I couldn't do in
Shanghai I couldn't do in
taong or New York you know we are going
to finish the whole thing which makes me
so happy you know this the first time
I'll finish the whole thing okay so
those are all the meditations today how
many are there
new ones three just three okay just
three first
one cocon yeah first one is cocoon
second one I'm
happy who made her happy okay third one
giving yeah giving but when you give
you're not staying in the thing you're
not staying in the thing
okay which means Buddha is moving on to
the emptiness of of things and not so
much
people how many things are there in the
world they will stop
okay opening
lines and all the lines I
remember yeah all the stuff in the world
we did it in level seven in Taiwan
there's two kinds they
are changing and changing things
changing things and unchanging things go
to the changing things there are three
kinds physical
things mental things and yeah like
Concepts like John John isn't something
you can chouch John is except for
but and John isn't John isn't
something that is a mind John is a
person so person is an idea so so
changing things there are three kinds
one easy physical stuff and then Minds
knowing things it's good to think of it
as knowing things and then in between
there there's ideas like Freedom or John
or okay Concepts
okay so so far we have like four things
okay we got unchanging things we got
change three changing things mine uh
physical stuff and stuff in the middle
by the way people are there persons are
there okay so if Lord Buddha is going to
cover all the things in the world if
Lord Buddha is going to teach all the
kinds of emptiness in the world he
should cover
roughly four things okay he already
covered this
one okay which was people and events
what was the
event giving the giving the act of
giving okay that's over here it's a
changing thing it involves physical and
mental things but it's a it's a just
like a synthesis okay so he's
covered he's covered this one people and
events okay but he's still got to
cover what is the emptiness of the
mind uh what is the emptiness of
physical things and what is the
emptiness of unchanging things and he's
going to he's going to cover all of them
okay and that's the rest of the this
part of the sit
Nick